A Guide to the Papers of K. Edward Lay
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Commercial Buildings
  - Commercial Buildings-Restaurants: Carroll's Tea Room, (Amoco; Spencer's Tea Room), Barracks Road and Emmet Street, 1937; Ivy Inn, (Pear Tree Toll House), Old Ivy Road, ca. 1845-1870; Tidbit and Overflow Cafe, E. High Street and U. S. 250, E. Market Street 1973-1996 (Box 30)
  - Commercial Buildings-Service Stations: Esmont Gas Station, ca. 1910-1930; Fry's Springs Gas Station, (Colonial Revival Service Station), Jefferson Park Avenue, 1932, 1939; Ragged Mountain Farm Gas Station, 20th century; (Gentry) Ray Gas Station, Ragged Mountain Farm Road, 1930s; Shell Gas Station, (Art Deco Service Station), E. High Street, 1939-1940; Texaco Gas Station, Barracks Road Shopping Center, Emmet Street, post 1958 1978-1995 (Box 30)
  - Commercial Buildings-Theaters: Jefferson Opera House; Lafayette Theater, E. Main Street, 1921, 1959 razed; Victory Hall, Scottsville, 1918-1920 1995 (Box 30)
  - Commercial Buildings-Theaters: Jefferson Theater, (Jefferson National Bank; Movie Palace), Main Street Mall, 1901, 1912, 1925 1979-1994 (Box 30)
  - Commercial Buildings-Theaters: Levy Opera House, (Town Hall), 1851-1852. 1888, 1981 1973-1995 (Box 30)
  - Commercial Buildings-Theaters: Paramount Theater, E. Main Mall, 1931 1981-2000 (Box 30)
  - Box 31
  - Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "A" - "B": Albemarle County Office Building, 1939; Albemarle Grocery Company Warehouse, South Street, 1916; Andrews-Bebas-Tripolas Building, Preston Avenue, 1915; Andrews-Michtom Building, W. Main Street, 1911; Angus Headquarters, 20th century; Armstrong Knitting Factory, Dale Avenue, 1889-1890; Henry Balz Buildings, W. Main Street, 1882-1884; A. G. Bennett Building, W. Main Street, 1910; C. M. Brand Dormitory, W. Main Street, ca. 1855; Brand-Chewning Building, W. Main Street, ca. 1856, ca. 1910-1917; Brown Milling Company Building, Avon Street, 1902; Buck Island Brick Factory and Slate Quarry sites, Simeon, 19th century; Bunch Building, Main Street, 1874 Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "C": C & A Railway Company, Virginia Public Service Company Building, W. Main Street, ca. 1914, ca. 1920s, 1978; Carpenter-Theodose Building, W. Main Street, ca. 1875; Carter-Bennett Building (Victory Shoe Store), W. Main Street, 1921; A. G. Carter Building, W. Main Street, 1922; Chancellor Building, University Avenue, ante 1891 and/or 1920; Charlottesville Agriculture and Iron Works, W. Main Street, 1858; Charlottesville Businesses, 19th century; Coca Cola Bottling Plant, Preston Avenue, 1939; Cooke Office Building, Gordon Avenue; ca. 1895; Collins Building, (Piedmont Furniture Company), E. Main Street, 1928; Conway & Oberdorfer Building, E. Main Street, 1915; Crozet Warehouse, (Apple Storage Warehouse), 1929; Cushman Building, (Cash Food Mart), W. Main Street, 1937 1980s-1990s (Box 31)
  - Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "D" - "F": Daniel Building, Fourth Street N.E., 1878, 1880, 1884; Dickerson-Williams Building, E. Main Street, 1903, 1929, 1955, 1982; J. E. Early Building, Fifth Street N.E., 1903; Early-Walker Building, Fifth Street N.E., 1897; Ellington Building, W. Main Street, 1914; Farish-Driscoll Building, E. Main Street, 1892; Fellini's Restaurant, Second Street N.W., 1860s, 1978; Feuchtenberger Building, W. Main Street, 1913-1914; Frizzell Building, (Old Fellows Hall), E. Market Street, 1884, ca. 1910 Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "G" - "H": Gianniny-Pace Building, W. Main Street, 1890; Gillespie-Tilman Building, Fourth Street N.E., 1884; Gilmore Furniture Company Building, E. Main Street, 1909-1910; Gleason Buildings, E. Main Street, 1927, 1928; Gleason-Robey Building, W. Main Street, 1989, 1939, 1956-1958; H. H. Hankins Warehouse, South Street W., 1916; Hartman Memorials, E. Market Street, mid 20th century; Heller Building, E. Main Street, 1896; Holsinger Photography Studio, W. Main Street, 1934; Holsinger-Thomas Building, W. Main Street, 1915 1980s-1990s (Box 31)
  - Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "I" - "L": Irving-Way-Hill/Hoff Motor Company Building, E. Main Street, 1910, 1953-1954, 1981; Jones-Bennett Building, E. Main Street, 1843; Jones-Wood Building, E. Main Street, 1843; Joseph Building, W. Main Street, 1918; Kaufman Building, E. Main Street, 1883, 1929; Keller Building, (Keller & George), E. Main Street, 1915; Kelly-Bragg Storehouse, E. Jefferson, 1826, 1921; King Lumber Company Warehouse, Preston Avenue, 1909; King's Warehouse, (Charles King & Sons Company), E. Water Street, 1897, 1907, 1980s; Krulewitch-Walters Warehouse, W. Main Street, 1895, 1905; L & S Building II, Third Street N.E., 1960-1961; Leitch Storehouse, Court Square, ca. 1820; Letterman Company Building, W. Main Street, 1899, 1911; Lewis Building, W. Main Street, 1901, 1981; Linney-Gleason & Valentine-Charlie Building, E. Main Street, 1895-1896, 1978; Lobban-George Buildings, E. Main Street, 1860 Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "M" - "P": Main Street Businesses, late 19th century; Marguerite's Brothel, (Marguietta's Bordello; Madam Marguerite de Crescioli, owner and operator), Fifth Street, 19th century; Martin Hardware, E. Market Street, 1902-1907; McKennie-Cook Building, University Avenue, ante 1891, 1927; Michie Printing Company, E. Market and Seventh Streets, 1900; Monticello Dairy, Grady Avenue, 1937, 1947, 1959, 1964; Norman Building, E. Main Street, 1896, ca. 1956; Norman-Spitzer Building, E. Main Street, 1896, 1915, ca. 1956; Oberdorfer-Robinson Building, E. Main Street, 1879; Old's Iron Furnace and Forge, (Albemarle Iron Furnace), 1769; Payne & Flannagan Building, E. Main Street, 1916; Perley Furniture and Undertaking Building, W. Main Street, 19th century; Peyton-Ellington Building, W. Main Street, 1893 1980s-1990s (Box 31)
  - Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "R" - "S": Randolph Building, E. Jefferson Street, 1957; Rea-Wood Building, Fifth Street N.E., 1905; Rinehart Building, E. Main Street, 1915; Rinehart- Gleason Building, (H. M. Gleason & Co.), Garrett Street, 1915; Samuel J. Robinson Building, E. Main Street, 1916; Scottsville Canal Tobacco Warehouse, 1834; Scottsville Factory, Valley Street, ca. 1835; Shapero Building, W. Main Street, 1911; Shapero-Moss Building, W. Main Street, 1896, 1937; Shepherd Building, (Mary L. Holland Shop), W. Main Street, 1913, 1967, 1983; Southern Bakery Building, Preston Avenue, 1940-1941, 1952, 1956, 1966; Sterling-Hawkins Buildings, E. Main Street, 1897 Commercial Buildings-Miscellaneous: "T" - "Y": Tilman Building, (J. D. & J. S. Tilman's), E. Main Street, 1916, 1956; Timberlake-Newman Building, E. Main Street, 1860-1867, 1914, 1976; Titus Nursery Building, (Waynesboro Nurseries Stone Building), Albemarle/Nelson, ca. 1910-1940; Turner-Tilman Buildings, Fourth Street N.E., 1884; Valentine-Charlie Building, E. Main Street, 1895-1896, 1978; Vinegar Hill, (Random Row; Smith's Row; Williams' Row), Preston Avenue and W. Main Street & end of Mall; A. P. Walker Building, Fifth Street, 1912; Walters Building, W. Main Street, 1898; Warren Distillery (Stillhouse), ca. 1786; Wingfield-Lacy Building, Fourth Street N.E., 1881, 1931; Young Building, Carlton Avenue, 1916 1980s-1990s (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises-Airports: Central Virginia Airports; Charlottesville-Albemarle Airport, 1994-1999 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises: Court Square Complex 1999 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises-Transportation: Bridges 1995-1999 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises-Transportation: Canals, Dams, Locks 1983-1998 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises-Transportation: Ferries 1973-1984 (Box 31)
  - Commercial Enterprises-Transportation: Roads 1991-1996 (Box 31)
  - Government and Public Buildings: Albemarle County Courthouse 1939-1996 (Box 31)
  - Government and Public Buildings: Albemarle County Jail 1974-1999 (Box 31)
  - Government and Public Buildings-Miscellaneous: Batesville Jail, (Old Jail; Tomlin House); late 19th century; Charlottesville City Hall, end of Downtown Mall, 1967; Charlottesville Post Office, E. Market Street, 1906, 1936; Earlysville Post Office, Route 663, ante 1850; McIntire Library, (Albemarle County Historical Society), Second Street N. E., 1919-1922; Revolutionary War Barracks, (The Barracks), Garth Road, 1779-1780; Virginia National Guard Armory, Eighth and E. Jefferson Streets, 20th century; Water Street Fire Station, (Vinegar Hill Fire House), early 20th century 1989-1999 (Box 31)
- Albemarle County-Miscellaneous Research
  - Albemarle County: African-Americans 1996 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Archaeology 1973-1994 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Cemeteries 1991-1996 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Cemetery Records n.d. (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Civil War 1975-1998 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: "Colonial Albemarle/The Social and Economic History of Piedmont Virginia County, 1727-1775" by Charles Wilder Watts 1948 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Communities 1965-1994 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Court Records 1990-1994 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Farm Estates 1989-1990 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Ghosts 1982-1995 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Historic Sites Lists 1931-1978 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: History 1954-1996 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Important Personages 1973-1995 (Box 32)
  - Albemarle County: Land Patents 1990 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Land Sales listed in Newspapers 1991-1994 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Lists of Buildings 1978-1997 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Lists of Drawings of Buildings 1989 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Lists of Photographs of Buildings 1988-1992 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Lists of Photographs of Buildings by Francis B. Johnston n.d. (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Maps 1991 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Massie Map Index 1995 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: McRaven Projects 1994 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Miscellaneous Buildings 1976-1995 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Monticello Plats n.d. (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Museum of Early Southern Decorative Arts (MESDA) 1975-1995 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Mutual Assurance Society Records 1988-1993 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: National Register of Historic Places and Virginia Landmarks Register 1997-1999 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Newspapers 1984-1987 (Box 33)
  - Albemarle County: Obituaries and Marriages 1949-1961 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Plats 1988-1989 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Population Census 1990-1991 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Preservation Ordinance 1996 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Real Estate and Personal Property Tax Analyses 1981-1982 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Real Estate and Personal Tax Records 1990-1995 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Sanborn Insurance Maps n.d. (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Statues 1993-2000 (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: United States Geological Survey Topographical Maps n.d. (Box 34)
  - Albemarle County: Virginia Department of Historic Resources (VDHR) Alphabetical and Numerical Indices 1986-1995 (Box 35)
  - Albemarle County: Virginia Department of Historic Resources (VDHR) Summary 1994 (Box 35)
  - Albemarle County: Works Project Administration (WPA) Historical Inventory 1992 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: Historic Landmarks Commission 1985-1992 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: Historic Landmarks Study 1976-1981 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: History 1958-1999 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: Maps 1988-1996 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: Mutual Assurance Society Records 1988-1990 (Box 35)
  - Charlottesville: National Register District 1981 (Box 36)
  - Charlottesville: News 1968-1977 (Box 36)
  - Charlottesville: Plats of Nimrod Bramham Property 1985 (Box 36)
  - Charlottesville: Plats with Original Lot Owners 1991 (Box 36)
  - Scottsville, General 1973-1997 (Box 36)
  - Scottsville: Plats n.d. (Box 36)
  - Scottsville: Studies 1998 (Box 36)
  - Southwest Mountains Area Natural Resource and History Preservation Study/Piedmont Environmental Council 1989 (Box 36)
  - Southwest Mountains Historic District/Piedmont Environmental Council 1991-1992 (Box 36)
  - Southwest Mountains Maps/Piedmont Environmental Council 1989 (Box 36)
- Virginia-Miscellaneous Research
  - Amherst County 1974-2000 (Box 37)
  - Augusta County 1992-1998 (Box 37)
  - Botetourt County 1970-1971 (Box 37)
  - Buckingham County 1969-1998 (Box 37)
  - Charles City County 1983 (Box 37)
  - Cumberland County 1973-1977 (Box 37)
  - Eastern Shore 1975-1977 (Box 37)
  - Faquier County 1979 (Box 37)
  - Fluvanna County 1955-1998 (Box 37)
  - Fluvanna County: Bremo and Palmyra 1990-1996 (Box 37)
  - Fluvanna County: Courthouse and Jail 1996-1998 (Box 37)
  - Fluvanna County: Soil Survey 1958 (Box 37)
  - Frederick County n.d. (Box 37)
  - Fredericksburg 1975 (Box 37)
  - Gloucester County n.d. (Box 37)
  - Goochland County 1969-1979 (Box 37)
  - Greene County 1974-1996 (Box 38)
  - Halifax County 1983-1994 (Box 38)
  - Hanover County 1993-1997 (Box 38)
  - Loudoun County 1982 (Box 38)
  - Loudoun County: Leesburg 1966-1978 (Box 38)
  - Loudoun County: Waterford 1981-1995 (Box 38)
  - Louisa County 1971-1995 (Box 39)
  - Louisa County: Studies 1970-1975 (Box 39)
  - Madison County 1979-2000 (Box 39)
  - Mecklenburg County 1963-1994 (Box 39)
  - Nelson County (2 folders) 1955-1997 (Box 39)
  - Nelson County: Cabell Family Houses-Soldier's Joy 1976-1998 (Box 39)
  - Nelson County: Cabell Family Houses- Union Hill and others 1969-1994 (Box 39)
  - Nelson County: Edward Coles House 1983-1991 (Box 40)
  - Nelson County: Lucy Gilliam Crocklin Correspondence 1993-1994 (Box 40)
  - Nelson County: Mills 1969-1992 (Box 40)
  - Nelson County: Oak Ridge 1981-1992 (Box 40)
  - Orange County 1973-1999 (Box 40)
  - Orange County: Montpelier 1973-1998 (Box 40)
  - Orange County: Studies 1989-1990 (Box 40)
  - Page County n.d. (Box 40)
  - Pittsylvania County 1982 (Box 40)
  - Powhatan County n.d. (Box 40)
  - Prince Edward County 1980 (Box 40)
  - Richmond n.d. (Box 40)
  - Shenandoah Natural Park Structures 1976 (Box 40)
  - Stafford County n.d. (Box 40)
  - Surry County 1977 (Box 40)
  - Vernacular Architecture 1973-1991 (Box 40)
  - Virginia Buildings Exhibit 1990 (Box 40)
  - Virginia Folk-Architecture 1973-1974 (Box 40)
  - Virginia Genealogy: Alphabetical n.d. (Box 41)
  - Virginia Genealogy: Carr, Dabney, Moon, Watson, and related families, compiled by Marion Gordon Shaw (3 folders) n.d. (Box 41)
  - Virginia Genealogy: Moon and Barclay families, compiled by Anna Mary Moon 1939 (Box 41)
  - Virginia Genealogy: Thomas Martin Thacker Papers 1989 (Box 41)
    Bound volume of photocopies of research materials, sketches, genealogical information, and correspondence of Thomas Martin Thacker, including a reconstruction based on textual evidence of Peter Jefferson's Shadwell Mills.
  - Virginia Genealogy: Reference n.d. (Box 42)
  - Virginia Genealogy: Williams and Rodes families 1980 (Box 42)
  - Virginia Land Transaction Methods; U. S. Geological Survey Maps 1986-1991 (Box 42)
  - Virginia Reminiscences: Recollections of Judge Richard Thomas Walker Duke, Jr. (1853-1926), transcription 1993 (Box 42)
  - Virginia Maps: Roads and River Corridors 1994 (Box 42)
  - Virginia Truss Bridges 1975 (Box 42)
  - West Virginia-Jefferson County 1981 (Box 42)
- University of Virginia Buildings
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Articles 1946-1998 (Box 42)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Brochures 1980s-1990s (Box 42)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Correspondence, Notes and Drawings 1976-1998 (Box 42)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Newspaper clippings (2 folders) 1973-1999 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Non-Jeffersonian 1981-1991 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Academical Village: Studies 1984-1996 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Fraternities 1979-1995 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Fraternities: "Fraternity Houses at the University of Virginia/Their History, Their Architecture" 1981 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Miscellaneous 1995 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings and related-Newspaper clippings (2 folders) 1974-2000 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Non-Jeffersonian 1980-1993 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Non-Jeffersonian: "Unbuilt Buildings at the University of Virginia" 1990 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia Buildings-Varsity Hall (Infirmary) 1977 (Box 43)
  - University of Virginia and Thomas Jefferson-Brochures and Seminar Printings 1976-1997 (Box 44)
  - University of Virginia and Thomas Jefferson-Chapters and Portions from Books 1905-1991 (Box 44)
  - University of Virginia and Thomas Jefferson-Correspondence and Notes 1982-1997 (Box 44)
  - University of Virginia and Thomas Jefferson-Magazine Articles and Bulletins 1976-1997 (Box 44)
- Thomas Jefferson and his Architects
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Joseph Antrim n.d. (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Thomas R. Blackburn 1998 (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-William John Coffee 1987-1994 (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Dabney Cosby 1968-1999 (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-James Dinsmore 1993-1998 (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-William & John Dunkum 1985-1996 (Box 44)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-John Gorman n.d. (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-John Jordan 1963-1988 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-John Neilson (2 folders) 1986-2000 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-James Oldham 1991-1997 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-John M. Perry; George Wilson Spooner, Jr. 1986-1995 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-William B. Phillips; Malcolm F. Crawford; Richard S. Boulware 1986-1996 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Buildings-Articles and other Writings (2 folders) 1949-1994 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Attributed Dwellings and Buildings 1951(1972-2000) (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Census 1987-1988 (Box 45)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Deed Books 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Marriage Records and Wills 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Newspaper Records 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Order Books 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Court Records: Personal Property and Land Tax 1987-1988 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Genealogies 1983-1985 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-Lists of Names and Data 1983-1993 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-References: Archives, Special Collections, University of Virginia Library 1986-1987 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-References: Thomas Jefferson Papers, Special Collections, University of Virginia Library 1986-1991 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-References: Various, Special Collections, University of Virginia Library 1986-1987 (Box 46)
  - Thomas Jefferson Builders-References: University of Virginia Libraries 1982-1986 (Box 46)
- University of Virginia Architecture Studios and Projects
  - Architecture Studios-Field Trips 1966-1980 (Box 47)
  - Architecture 81-Community Involvement 1971 (Box 47)
  - Architecture 513-Measured Drawings 1973-1998 (Box 47)
  - Architecture 401 Studio 1975 Fall (Box 47)
  - Architecture 402 Studio 1977 Spring (Box 47)
  - Architecture 512 Studio-Recording Historic Buildings 1978-1996 (Box 47)
  - Architecture 302 Design Studio 1979 Spring (Box 47)
  - Architecture 302 Design Studio 1980 Spring (Box 47)
  - Architecture 502 & 511-Fieldwork in Preservation 1980 (Box 47)
  - Architecture 302 Design Studio 1981 Spring (Box 47)
  - Architecture 301 Studio 1981 Fall (Box 47)
  - Architecture 401 Design Studio 1982 Fall (Box 47)
  - Architecture Course-Virginia Road Traces, Road Survey Course 1982 Fall (Box 47)
  - Architecture 302 Design Studio 1983 Spring (Box 47)
  - Architecture 401 Design Studio 1983 Fall (Box 47)
  - Architecture 402 Design Studio 1984 Spring (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1984 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture 401 Design Studio 1985 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture Plan 834-Recording Virginia Historic Buildings 1985-1998 (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1986 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture Project-Architectural Pattern Associated with Virginia Road Traces 1986 (Box 48)
  - Architecture 402 Design Studio 1987 Spring (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1987 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture 402 Design Studio 1988 Spring (Box 48)
  - Architecture 402 Design Studio 1989 Spring (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1989 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1990 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture 302 Design Studio 1991 Spring (Box 48)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1991 Fall (Box 48)
  - Architecture 512P Design Studio-Architectural Surveys 1991 Fall (Box 49)
  - Architecture 301 Design Studio 1992 Fall (Box 49)
  - Architecture 513P Design Studio-Measured Drawings 1993 Spring (Box 49)
  - Architecture 401 Design Studio 1993 Fall (Box 49)
  - Architecture Project-Virginia Road Traces: Building Lists 1995 (Box 49)
  - Architecture Project-Building Conservations Studies, Professor Matthias E Kayhoe n.d. (Box 49)
- University of Virginia Miscellaneous
  - Architectural Drawings of University of Virginia Buildings in Special Collections Library 1989-1990 (Box 50)
  - Architectural Drawings of University of Virginia Buildings in Physical Plant [Facilities Management] Library 1991 (Box 50)
  - Architectural History at UVa: Alumni, Faculty and Theses, 1958-1996 1996 (Box 50)
  - Architectural References 1996-1998 (Box 50)
  - Architecture of the South Series 1989-1990 (Box 50)
  - Architecture Projects Lists- Architecture in Virginia Series: Regional Architecture & Recording Historic Virginia Buildings; Measured Drawings, Studies in Vernacular Architecture; Architecture Associated with Virginia Road Traces 1973-1998 (Box 50)
  - Architecture School and Faculty 1994-1998 (Box 50)
  - Architecture School History 1988-1999 (Box 50)
  - Art Index 1982-1992 (Box 50)
  - Employees' Lists, 1817-1940 1989-1990 (Box 50)
  - Maps and Plats of the University of Virginia n.d. (Box 50)
  - Names Committee (2 folders) 1986-1993 (Box 50)
- Contemporary Architects Research
  - David Wiley Anderson 1997-1998 (Box 51)
  - Thomas Rolander Blackburn 1999 (Box 51)
  - Joseph Norwood Bosserman 1997-1998 (Box 51)
  - Eugene Bradbury 1984 (Box 51)
  - Edmund Schureman Campbell 1988-1998 (Box 51)
  - Thomas Kevin Fitz Patrick 1996 (Box 51)
  - Charles and George Sidney Ford 1996 (Box 51)
  - Charles Freeman Gillette 1993-1994 (Box 51)
  - Milton Grigg 1982-1998 (Box 51)
  - William Newton Hale, Jr. 1982-1994 (Box 51)
  - Henderson Heyward 1987-1999 (Box 51)
  - Joseph Fairman Hudnut 1991 (Box 51)
  - Floyd Johnson 1987-1999 (Box 51)
  - Sidney Fiske Kimball 1983-1995 (Box 51)
  - Alfred Lawrence Kocher 1987-1995 (Box 51)
  - James R. Magruder 1988-1996 (Box 51)
  - Stanislaw Makielski 1988-1998 (Box 51)
  - Louie L. Scribner 1982-1990 (Box 51)
  - Marshall Swain Wells 1982-1998 (Box 51)
  - Clarence Windom Wenger 1983-1984 (Box 51)
  - Waddy Butler Wood 1998 (Box 51)
  - Architects' Vitae 1993-1994 (Box 52)
  - Local and Virginia Architects n.d. (Box 52)
  - Local Colonial Revival Architects 1982-1985 (Box 52)
- Architecture Correspondence
  - Architecture Correspondence 1970-1975 (Box 52)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1976-1979 (Box 52)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1980-1982 (Box 52)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1983 (Box 52)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1984 (Box 53)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1985 (Box 53)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1986 (Box 53)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1987 (Box 53)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1988 (Box 53)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1989 (Box 54)
  - Architecture Correspondence 1990 (Box 54)